ESMA ERDEM

Bangor, ME | 207-412-8936 | esmaerdem94@gmail.com | Linkedin | Github | Portfolio

SUMMARY

Highly motivated Software Engineer with entry-level experience in software development, Python and Javascript. Equipped with proven problem-solving and analytical thinking skills gained through Astronautical Engineering with High Honors Degree and a track record of success in team leadership and effective communication in my previous role as a sales manager. Excited to combine my technical skills and business acumen to drive impactful results and grow with the company.

SKILLS

(proficient): Python, JavaScript, Git, SQL (familiar): Matlab, Fortran

PROJECTS

Wicked Acadia Wicked Acadia Live GitHub Repo

Apr 2023 - May 2023

- Developed a comprehensive platform to assist nature enthusiasts in planning visits to Acadia National Park.
- Integrated user-friendly features, such as user authentication/authorization with advanced security practices, and favorites/bookmarks functionality for enhanced user experience.
- Designed an efficient RESTful API to enable caching external API data for increasing efficiency.
- Incorporated Object-Relational Mapping (ORM) techniques to architect and establish relational database models.
- Embraced Object Oriented programming principles to enhance code reusability and maintainability.
- Implemented extensive documentation and rigorous unit tests, including Flask integration tests, to achieve bug-free and maintainable code.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Student, Springboard Software Engineering | Remote

Jan 2023 - Current

- Developed and deployed web applications, gaining experience in web application architecture and functionality.
- Applying clean and concise programming practices, prioritizing collaborative code readability and efficiency.
- Completed a wide range of hands-on projects, developing diverse web applications and implementing various data structures.
- Emphasizing documentation and rigorous testing for bug-free, maintainable code.
- Creating relational databases through SQL and enhancing functionality with API integration.

Sales Manager, Cool As A Moose | Provincetown, MA

Jan 2019 - Sept 2022

- Achieved 70% revenue growth in the first year through effective customer service and strategic planning.
- Conducted regular health checks on the point-of-sale system and analyzed inventory data using software.
- Developed and executed successful marketing campaigns, increasing brand visibility and community engagement.

EDUCATION & CERTIFICATIONS

Springboard | Online

Software Engineering Certification

- Key aspects of front-end web development, back-end web development, databases, and data structures and algorithms. Included 1:1 industry expert mentor oversight, and completion of in-depth portfolio projects.
- Honed skills in Data Structures, and Algorithms, Web Development, JavaScript, AJAX, Git, SQL, PostgreSQL, Python, Flask, Node.js, Express, Jasmine, Jest, Cypress, HTML/CSS.

Turkish Aeronautical Association University | Ankara, Turkiye

BS Astronautical Engineering, 3.29

- Relevant Coursework: Algorithmic Computer Programming, Linear Algebra, Computational Methods, Control Systems, Attitude Determination and Control, Plasma Physics and Engineering
- Acquired advanced algorithmic and computational skills through rigorous coursework and an immersive internship experience. Self-taught Matlab and expertly applied these skills to successfully complete internship projects and subsequent coursework.